GAIL GIBBONS

GailGibbons@Outlook.co

267.221.9799

Opvlestown, PA 18901

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Resourceful healthcare consultant with a solid clinical background over 20+ years management in the field. Knowledgeable about optimization strategies and evidence-based practices. Excellent problem-solving, planning and communication skills combined with a decisive and analytical nature.

SKILLS

- · Clinical Management
- · Evidenced-based medicine
- Population Health
- Quality and Content management
- Program and product development
- Managing Operations and Efficiency
- Medical coding
- Excellent writing and communication

EDUCATION

Gwynedd Mercy University Gwynedd Valley, PA

MSM/MBA: Master of Science: Business Administration And Management

Temple University Philadelphia, PA

Bachelor of Arts: Science And

Arts

WORK HISTORY

OPTUM SERVICES, INC /UNITED HEALTHCARE - ASSOCIATE DIRECTOR

Minnetonka, MN • 01/2016 - 10/2022

- Developed quality measures/clinical indicators, medical coding strategies for system capabilities collaborating with medical directors and cross-functional teams to improve quality gaps in care.
- Aligned enterprise clinical consistency with clinical evidence, coding solutions and governance.
- Created, reviewed, and edited multiple communications including policies, clinical messaging, care alerts, clinical algorithms, annual program quality plans, evidenced-based guideline content with cross functional teams including operations, health economics, and product enterprise-wide to improve CMS, state, and regulatory compliance.

ALERE, LLC - VICE PRESIDENT, CLINICAL INTEGRITY and COMPLIANCE

Atlanta, GA • 01/2011 - 01/2016

- Managed all aspects of clinical program development collaborating with cross functional teams to identify market leaders with over 100 clients in Disease/Case Management population health programs and associated clinical governance.
- · Collaborated with all levels of organization to diversify,

Gwynedd Mercy UniversityGwynedd Valley, PA

Associate of Science: Science

of Nursing

Website: https://www.

Gail-Gibbons.com

- launch, and expand products to capture new business.
- Oversight and design of chronic clinical program reporting measures, content with governance, clinical education, and other collateral interventions.
- Analyzed, reviewed programs, translated clinical evidence, researched, and established benchmarks to optimized program strategy and exceed clinical performance.
- Organized and facilitated medical advisory panel.

MATRIA HEALTHCARE, INC - DIRECTOR, CLINICAL PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT

Atlanta, GA • 01/2008 - 01/2011

- Developed clinical programs, content and metrics for clinical outcomes collaboratively with product and crossfunctional teams throughout product life-cycle. Moved from five chronic programs to 50 within 3 years.
- Researched targeted population and clinical evidence to support strategic direction. Performed claim analysis, and research supporting innovative program design.
- Liaised with internal and external customers and advisory board stakeholders for shared decision content, performance guarantees, procurement, algorithms, requirements, and regulatory changes.

COR SOLUTIONS MEDICAL, INC - MANAGER OF CLINICAL OPERATIONS

Plymouth Meeting, PA • 01/1999 - 01/2008

- Oversaw overall clinical operation of nursing services and patient care management for high profiled employer and managed care clients in population health.
- Planned and managed adherence to project budget, contract expectations, implementation and assisted in identification and development of program systematic clinical algorithms.
- Established and maintained contacts at various management levels regarding clinical operations department and specific projects.
- Regularly evaluated employee performance and provided feedback.
- Identified opportunities to improve clinical practices, devised strategies and implemented plans to increase patient care standards and enhance operational

procedures.